Mohd Kamaal

Full stack engineer

♣ +91-9719892233 @ kamaalmohd79@gmail.com ② https://kamaalmohd79.github.io
♥ Chandigarh, INDIA

SUMMARY

Innovative full stack developer with over 3+ years of experience in building usable, useful, well-constructed and maintaining responsive websites in several industries. Proficient with Node.js, React.js, Vue.js and Next.js along with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and many libraries and Framework as well as handled backend nodejs components methods to creating of API's with the data object models.

Translate designs to front end code, estimate time and costs and determine developer requirements and specifications along with collaborating with creative and development teams on execution of ideas and projects. Interested in continuation of learning and cooperation with excellent people.

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering

Uttarakhand Technical University

12/2016 - 06/2020 Dehradun, UK GPA 3.9 / 5.0

PROJECTS

Voyage-dApp

05/2022 - Ongoing Netherlands https://oyster-app-qvxp9.ondigitalocean.app

Technologies: Reactjs, Redux-toolkit, chakra-ui, sass, Nodejs & Mysql.

It is a decentralization web app which is interacted between Project and holder is to communicate messages, post feeds by the project to readonly it by holder.

- Implemented many functionalities like authentication and Api's and catching it for use across the application integration to get, post, put and delete any item or data instance.
- Implemented Login and Signup and to deal with state management tool within an app.
- Had implemented functional based components in this app by providing the latest react hooks features.
- implemented a react redux toolkit library (its latest state management tool provided by react) to manage its state with the functional components.

YouCast

01/2022 - 05/2022 Egypt https://galileo-masters Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Bootstrap, Nodejs & MySql.

To collect the information of participants auditioning in a film industry mainly for the film director. He can get the detail of each candidate like profile of candidates, profile pictures in every angle, body gestures, face, acting ability provided in a short clip etc. Everything is well managed in this web app to elaborate the properties of a particular candidate.

- Developed Backend and frontend interface to define the admin, dashboard panel, filters tools and various functionalities developed in JavaScript.
- Defined various methods such as react-redux to store the data into state used actions to dispatch, used reducers to come into action of store data and developed a well managed state management system.

SKILLS

Technologies

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • React • Nodejs •

Next • Vue • Redux • TypeScript • Bootstrap •

Redux-Toolkit • Vuex • Github • Expressjs •

MySql • MongoDb • Jira • Material-ui •

Redux-Thunk

Development & Operations

Jest • Mocha • Scrum • Agile • GitHub •

GitBucket · Azure DevOps · Digital Ocean

EXPERIENCE

Software Trainee

APPWRK IT Solutions

01/2020 - 06/2020 Chandigarh

Joined Appwrk It Solutions as a trainee, started web developer career from this orgainisation. gained opportunities to elaborate myself in the field of Software Development.

- Learned basic technologies to implement a web app like html, css, sass, javascript, bootstrap.
- Learned how to collabarate with team by doing work.
- Worked with Core JavaScript to develop automated solutions to include web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Web services

Frontend Software Engineer

APPWRK IT Solutions

06/2020 - 02/2022 Chandigarh Here I got to work in JavaScript stack technologies to implement and build functionalities with the proper well logics.

- Worked in main steam of project to develop frontend web app using Reactjs & Redux.
- Simultaneously created & maintained frontend part of web app by perfomed actions using framework.
- Worked in live projects to deal with clients requirements and develop a proper required tasks.
- Designed and Developed UI design using CSS, HTML, Javascript, React & Vue.
- Developed landing pages dashboards & online applications using Javascript, Reactis & Nextis.

PROJECTS

Noteworthy.AI

06/2021 - 12/2021 Canada https://noteworthy.ai

To Noteworthy Al's solution, Inspector, reduces the need for dedicated distribution asset inspections and mitigates risk at-scale while reducing cost

The Inspector hardware sensors and AI edge processing arrays mount on existing fleet vehicles and automatically geolocate, inventory and identify pole-top component defects while vehicles perform routine operations, reducing the need to mobilize dedicated inspection teams.

- In this project, I have worked to apply the changes in the distributed images and analyses the frame of data.
- Worked on it to analyze the data coming from APIs and managing it to the functions.
- · Resolved many such bugs that was very tricky to debug and inspect.
- · Created functions to handle the events & operations.

PassingPlan

01/2021 - 06/2021 California https://passingplan.com Technologies: Vue.js, Vuetify, Node.js, ASP.net, MySQL

It is divided into two sections or we can say it has two roles as Provider & Planner (users). Planner can request or order any categorized service at their doorstep or as delivery to doorstep. And Provider can see all the orders and handle them into their respective manner or deliver with the respective time slot.

- Developed various operations like Provided Roles, Provider & Planner sections, Authentication, Frontend behavior of app, Vuetify forms, inputs & Components (Vuetify is a Vue UI Library with beautifully handcrafted Material Components).
- · Defined the functions & methods to behave the functionalities well.
- Derived the state management system to handle data into a well organized form & data can be call into any components dynamically.
- Mapped APIs frontend to backend and structured them into a individually components by the well managed hierarchy tree.

Volta

09/2020 - 12/2020 San Francisco https://voltacharging.com Technologies: Vue.js, MySQL, amCharts, Vuetify forms.

This website is developed for government sector as Power Corporation project. It's main purpose is to controls & tracks records of power supply supplied to agencies and keep an eye to maintain the stability of power. Also tracked all the needed electricity & energy information into graphs. All the agencies have separate accounts, roles & authentication.

- · Created the JavaScript functionality and graphs components as well.
- Implemented data into graphs with the help of amCharts (amCharts is a set of JavaScript-based data visualization libraries that includes regular chart types like Serial, Pie, etc. as well as advanced ones like Stock Charts and Maps).
- Created the components individually to understand the hierarchy tree.
- Created the scripts to maintain data into tabulation form and graph form, controlled data from APIs to manipulate into the tables and graphs with the various script functions.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Freelancer

02/2022 - Ongoing Chandigarh
As a freelancer I have working to develop full stack web application using the latest

stack web application using the latest technlogies like Nextjs, Reactjs, Nodejs & Vuejs.

- Backend created by implementing many models to deal with the backend objects with database tables. Created and Integrated Restful api's to deal with data objects and body data instantly via api twoway binding methods backend to frontend.
- Controlled frontend APIs into the structure hierarchy of the data coming from backend. Used various methods to synch data into form of images and frames.
- Gained hand-on experise in Bootstrap, Foundation, Express & similar backend Nodejs as well frontend presentaion frameworks web application frameworks.
- Played a key role in the development, improvement and operation of web based applications.

PROJECTS

V-Apps

06/2020 - 09/2020 Paris developer.v-apps.cloud Technologies: Vue.js, Vuetify, Laravel, MySQL

This project categorized in two main parts Admin & Users. User's part is categorized into many sub -sections like Employees, Contracts, Staff, Skills, Tools, Training, General, SDS, Booking Agenda & Systems. Its Frontend is created in Vue.js & Backend developed in Laravel, a framework provided by PHP.

- To maintain the stability find or debug the bugs and resolved it because this project contained huge amount of code even in a single component as every component created individually and imported many times in the form of parent to child or child to parent tree.
- Controlled the APIs of this project like various employees, contracts
 modules and functionalities. Also managed the authentication of vapps like to give role to any single or multiple users, to give
 permissions to login and define the roles to new users. Every
 components of v-apps defined uniquely to handle the code easily.
- Worked as backend developer on some parts like APIs, middleware's, store and index functions, roles & responsibility to develop user permission, models and controllers as it was created it on Laravel framework.
- Created the functions, methods properly by frontend into the backend to behave the functions well or to reduce the process time and retain the stability of SPA.